Alfred I. Hallowell Papers 1892-1981 Mss.Ms.Coll.26
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI - Photographs
  - Subseries E. St. Francis Abenaki Album, 1914-1920s, n.d.; Copy: 160 photos
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., left to right: Cecile Nolet, Josphine Capino, Sophie Nolet, and, [1920s]; E138
      William Nolet
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Bruno Obomsawin, [1920s]; E139
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Adelaide Obomsawin, [1920s]; E140
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Bessie "Bright Eyes" Tahamont, [1920s?]; E141
      Girl with racoon, daughter of Elijah (d)
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Marie Benedict Maria [?], [1920s]; E142
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Maude (Benedict) Nagazoa, Ruth or Mary Jane, [1920s]; E143
      See also: E144, E145, E146
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Ruth and Mary Jane, [1920s]; E144
      See also: E143, E145, E146
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Maude (Benedict) Nagazoa, Ruth and Mary Jane, [1920s]; E145
      See also: E143, E144, E146
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Ruth or Mary Jane, [1920s]; E146
      See also: E143, E144, E145
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Rose Capino, [1920s]; E147
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Fred Sadoques, [1920s]; E148
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; E149
      See also: E150, E151, E155, E156
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; E150
      See also: E149, E151, E155, E156
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; E151
      See also: E149, E150, E155, E156
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; E152
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Maria (Obomsawin) Denis, [1920s]; E153
      See also: E159, E160
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; E154
      See also: F21
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; E155
      See also: E149, E150, E151, E156
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; E156
      See also: E149, E150, E151, E155
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Edward Denis, [1920s]; E157
      See also: E158
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Edward Denis, [1920s]; E158
      See also: E157
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Maria (Obomsawim) Denis, [1920s]; E159
      See also: E153, E160
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Maria (Obomsawim) Denis, [1920s]; E160
      See also: E153, E159
  - Subseries F. Miscellaneous Native American, [1920s-1952, n.d.]; Copy (353 photos)
    Contains loose photographs originally grouped in envelopes. Some are duplicates of the images in the albums. Quality of the images vary greatly.
    Description of the reproduction photographs (7.5 boxes); 353 images. Where applicable, these have been cross-referenced to the albums. Some images from susbseries G are also represented in this series. Listed below is a breakdown of the images into tribe or group or location:
    F1-F37 Tribe/Group: Abnaki
    F38-F46 Location: Assawompsett, Wamponowag
    F47-F49 Location: Berens River. (Berens River "white folk")
    F59-F244 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa
    F245-F247 Tribe/Group: Mandan
    F248-F249 Location: Mashpee, [Mass.]
    F251-F254 Location: Manitou Rapids
    F255 Tribe/Group: Montagnais
    F256-F257 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa
    F258 Tribe Group: Nipissing
    F259-F271 Tribe/Group: Abnaki
    F272-F299 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa
    F300-F305 Tribe/Group: Tete de Boule
    F306 Tribe/Group: Abnaki? [Mohegan?]
    F307 Tribe/Group: Arikara?
    F308 Tribe/Group: [Abnaki?]
    F309-F311 Miscellaneous or unknown
    F312 Tribe/Group: [Ojibwa?]
    F313 Miscellaneous or unknown
    F314-F315 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa
    F316 Tribe/Group: Eskimo
    F317-F331 Miscellaneous
    F332-F333 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa
    F334-F337 Miscellaneous
    F338-F340 Tribe/Group: Abnaki (Abenaki)
    F341-F353 Tribe/Group: Ojibwa?
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Gertrude Nolet, August 1921; F1
      See also: E42, E44, E45, F4
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Bernedette Laurent, August 1921; F2
      See also: E33, E34, F3, F30
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Bernedette Laurent, August 1921; F3
      See also: E33, E34, F2, F30
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Eli Nolet family: Mrs. Anges Nolet, Eli Nolet, Cecile, August 1921; F4
      Nolet, Marie Alice d' Gonzag [d' Gonzaques?]
      See also: E39, E40, E41, E42, F1
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Beatrice Nolet, August 1921; F5
      See also: E119, E120, F7
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Doris Dauphinais, July 1922; F6
      See also: E126, E127, E128
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Beatrice Nolet, August 1921; F7
      See also: E119, E120, F5
    - St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F8
    - St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F9
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F10
      See also: F33
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F11
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Louis Napoleon Obomsawin, [1920s]; F12
      See also: E66, E67, E68
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Anna Panadis, [1920s]; F13
      See also: E58, E59
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F14
      See also: E24, F15
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F15
      See also: E24, F14
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F16
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Paul Gill, [1920s]; F17
      See also: E83, F18
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Paul Gill, [1920s]; F18
      See also: E83, F17
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Napoleon Robert Obomsawin, [1920s]; F19
      See also: E70
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F20
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F21
      See also: E154
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1914?]; F22
      See also: [E13, F28?] [New Council House?] Original photo: Dept. of Mines, Geological Survey, Photographic Div. #26858 June 4, 1914
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Veronica Nolet, [1920s]; F23
      Cousin of Eli Nolet
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Antoinette (de Gonzaques) Thibaudeau, [1914?]; F24
      See also: E124 Original photo: Dept. of Mines, Geological Survey, Photographic Division #26854 June 4, 1914
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F25
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F26
    - St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F27
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F28
      New Council House
      See also: E13, [F22?]
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F29
      See also: E23
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., Bernedette Laurent, August 1921; F30
      see also: E33, E34, F3
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F31
      See also: E97
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F32
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F33
      See also: F10
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F34
    - Abnaki, St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s]; F35
    - St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F36
      Native films
    - St. Francis, Odanak, P.Q., [1920s?]; F37
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F38
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F39
      Assawompsett from Phillips lookout
      See also: F40
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F40
      See also: F39
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F41
      Assawompsett showing Bettys neck
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F42
      Long Lake -- looking west
      See also: F43
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F43
      Long Lake
      See also: F42
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F44
      Lake Quittacas
      See also: F45
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F45
      Road crossing between Pocksha & Quittacas
      See also: F44, F46
    - Assawompsett, Wamponwag, [1920s?]; F46
      Pocksha -- looking west
    - Berens River, Alix family, [1930s]; F47
      Berens River white folk
    - Berens River, Alix family, [1930s]; F48
    - Berens River, Alix family, [1930s]; F49
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens & his wife Nancy Everett with family members., 1930 - 1932; F50
      Berens, Gordon; Berens, Nancy, Mrs., (ne Everett); Berens, William, Chief; Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens, 1930 - 1932; F51
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F56, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Nenawan, Maggie Duck, 1930s; F52
      Daughter of John Duck
      See also: A104
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ketagas Keeper, [1930s]; F53
      [A councilor of the Little Grand Rapids band]
      See also: A116
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabikwe, 'she has gray hair', (Mary Jane Keeper) Leveque., [1930s] [1938?]; F54
      Waabikwe, 'she has gray hair'. Mary Jane (Keeper) Leveque, married to Joe Leveque. See also: A122
      Leveque, Waapihkwe (Mary Jane Keeper); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Boys swimming, [1930s]; F55
      See also: A154, A155, A156
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens, [1930s]; F56
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F88, F89, F92, F164, F285
      Berens, William, Chief
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Moses Owen, [1933]; F57
      See also: A230, F148
      Owen, Miskwadezii Oshkiishik, (Moses)
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Enchokay (Stanley) Quill, [1930s]; F58
      See also: A289, A290, A291
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen and his wife Koowin., [1930s]; F59
      Naamiwan and wife Koowin and family members. He is holding a drumstick and rattle. Behind is his Waabano pavilion. See here inside pavilion both Aankus (Angus) Owen and Omishoosh ( Charlie George) Owen. (Naamiwan - 1851? - 1844 - J. Brown 2/96]
      Owen, Aankus, (Angus); Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind; Owen, Omishoosh, (Charlie George)
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Gii-sayinan, 'our brother'., 1930s; F60
      Gii-sayinan,'our brother' medicine man, maternal grandfather of Omishoosh (Charlie George) Owen of Pauingassi so father of both his mother and his aunt, Miskwa'o Owen.
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, [1930s]; F61
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Naamiwan's dream drum and drummers, [1930s]; F62
      Naamiwan's dream drum and drummers including three nephews of Naamiwan, Omishoosh (James) Owen and his brothers, Gezhiiyash (John) Owen, and Joozhi (Joseph Owen) Moose who brought Naamiwan's drum to Poplar River in the early 1920s. The drum was used in the Boodaade or "Ghost (or Spirit of the Dead) Dance" that originated with a dream of Naamawin's.
      Owen, Naamiwan, (John) Fair Wind
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen, 1933; F63
      [A conjurer and the son of John Owen (Fair Wind)]
      See also: A209, A210, A211, F64
      Owen, Aankus, (Angus); Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Religion; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Aankus (Angus) Owen, 1933; F64
      See also: A209, A210, A211, F63
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, 1934; F65
      Pi'kogan
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, woman with tikanagan, 1933; F66
      Ojibwa children--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s]; F68
      Boggs [?]
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Maamaan and Aamoo Duck, sons of John Duck, [1930s]; F69
      Prepared for ceremony. See also: F70
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Maamaan and Aamoo Duck, sons of John Duck, [1930s]; F70
      Prepared for ceremony. See also: F69
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids settlement, [1930s]; F71
      Summer fishing settlement showing a cluster of some dwelling types.
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Ketigaash Keeper and family, [1930s]; F72
      Ketigash Keeper his wife Shoowap and their children leaning against a waaginogaan in Little grand Rapids. Ketigash was head councillor for Little Grand Rapids. See also: A117
      Keeper, Ketigash; Keeper, Shoowap
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids. zhaabandowaan, [1930s]; F73
      Joe Keeper dwelling. See also: A89, A91, A93, F107
      Keeper, Joe; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boy, [1930s]; F74
      Child, Little Grand Rapids. See also: A118
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Nenk (Bushie) Owen., [1930s]; F75
      Nenk Bushie. Born 1907-08, died in Red Lake Feb 6, 1935. First married Achiik. Second marriage to Bashik, 'the deer' (Robert) Owen.
    - Berens River, Canoe with moose meat, [May 1952?]; F76
      Canoe with moose meat
    - Berens River, [May 1952?]; F77
    - Berens River, Bob Pine, Arnie Burns, May 1952; F78
      Sugar Camp
    - Berens River, [May 1952?]; F79
    - Berens River, Ed Mitchell, Rhonda Lee Mitchell, Jim Bell, May 1952; F80
    - Berens River, non-native couple, [May 1952?]; F81
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, older woman, [1930s]; F82
      D.M.S. negatives
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, fuzzy view of settlement and housing types, 1930s; F83
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, boy, [1930s]; F84
    - Berens River, teenage girl, [1930s]; F85
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano lodge, [1930s]; F86
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Treaty time, 1933; F87
      Treaty ground in Berens River. See also: A4, A5, A6, A7, A87, A88
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens by campfire smoking, 1930 - 1933; F88
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F89, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, William Berens by campfire smoking, 1930 - 1933; F89
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F92, F164, F285
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids family, [1930s]; F90
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, man with ceremonial pipe, [1930s]; F91
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Joe Keeper, William Berens, A. I. H., and Atoine Bittern, [1935?]; F92; Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974
      Joe Keeper, guide, Chief William Berens, Hallowell and Atoine Bittern who cooked when A. I. H. traveled up the Berens River - at Little Grand Rapids in front of H's tent.
      Berens, William, Chief; Bittern, Atoine; Keeper, Joe; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Social life and customs; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiwiich & Opashensh with octopus bag, drum stick and drum supports or ceremonial curved pole., [1930s]; F93
      See also: A113, A114, A115
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Keeper, Opashensh, 1866-1945; Ojibwa Indians--Canada; Ojibwa Indians--Medicine; Ojibwe people
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, men and boys gathered in front of Hallowell's tent, [1930s]; F94
    - Berens River, Little Grand Rapids dock, [1930s]; F95
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, man, [1930s]; F96
      [From Flambeau materials?]
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids family, [1930s]; F97
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, young man, [1930s]; F98
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, "en route", [1930s]; F99
    - Berens River, Moose rock painting, [1930s]; F100
      "En route" -- Moose Picture Rock
      See also: A80, A81, A82
    - Berens River, aerial view of forest fire, [1930s]; F101
      "En route" -- Closer view
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, waabano lodge, [1930s]; F102
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids family, [1930s]; F103
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Two men and a boy, [1930s]; F104
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Kiiwiich and Opashensh, [1930s]; F105
      Keeper, Kiiwiich, Alex, 1863-1944; Keeper, Opashensh, 1866-1945
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Keeper family, [1930s]; F106
      Keeper family
      Keeper, Joe
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Joe Keeper dwelling, 1934; F107
      [The Keeper dwelling?]
      See also: A89, A91, A93, F73
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F108
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F109
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F110
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F111
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934; F112
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1936; F113
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934 or 1936 [1936?]; F114
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934 or 1936 [1936?]; F115
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934 or 1936 [1936?]; F116
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934 or 1936 [1936?]; F117
      See also: F118
    - Ojibwa, Jack Head, 1934 or 1936 [1936?]; F118
      See also: F117
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, [1930s]; F119
      This little scene around the camp fire got blurred w/the smoke. This was taken on our way up. Photographer: Steve Boggs
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s]; F120
    - [Ojibwa?], [Berens River?], [1930s]; F121
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s]; F122
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F123
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A320, A321, F124, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F124
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A320, A321, F123, F125, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F125
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A320, A321, F123, F124, F126
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F126
      See also: A317, A318, A319, A320, A321, F123, F124, F125
    - Ojibwa, Dead Falls, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F127
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, [1930s]; F128
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, [1930s]; F129
    - Ojibwa, Duck Lake, [1930s]; F130
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F131
      Woman lifting net -- Pikangikum B
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F132
      See also: A315
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Left to right: 1. 2. Charolette Strang 3. 4. Booshe, [1930s]; F133
      See also: A314
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F134
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, [1930s]; F135
    - Ojibwa, Pikangikum, Joseph Crow & his first wife with rolls of birchbark house covers, [1930s]; F136
      See also: A294
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids sweat lodge convered, [1930s]; F137
      Ceremonies -- [Sweat Lodge] -- J. Brown 2/96
      See also: A177
    - Ojibwa, [Little Grand Rapids, ceremonial site, [1930s]; F138
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, site of Sweat lodge, [1930s]; F139
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Waabano ceremony, [1930s]; F140
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Dream Drum Ceremony with Kiiwiich and Ketigash, [1930s]; F141
      See also: A167
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Naamiwan (John) Owen 'Fair Wind' standing, [1930s] [1938?]; F142
      See also: A204, A205, A206, A207, F59
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Waanachense & Kaapech & 3 daughters [Alex Owen, Sr.?], [1930s] [1938?]; F143
      See also: A215, [A214?]
      Owen, Waanachense, (Alex)
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Maados and family, baby intikanagan has small drum, [1930s] [1938?]; F144
      See also: A228
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, rectangular ceremonial lodge, 1933; F145
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Boodaade of Dream Drum ceremonial lodge, 1933; F146
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, man, 1933; F147
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Moses Owen and wife, 1933; F148
      See also: A230, F57
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, possibly Elizabeth and Spoot, 1933; F149
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, camp site?, [1930s]; F150
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, three men, [1930s]; F151
      Old site of the Hudson Bay Company near encampment B
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, rest stop, [1930s]; F152
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, travelling by canoe, 1938; F153
      See also: A76
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, James Bearhair Owen & family [Mahkikaat or Maahkikaat?], [1930s] [1938?]; F154
      See also: A212, A213, F163
      Owen, Niizhishaan, (James Bearhair)
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Alix children, [1930s] [1938?]; F155
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Alix child?, [1930s] [1938?]; F156
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Mrs. Alix?, [1930s] [1938?]; F157
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Mr. Alix?, [1930s]; F158
      See also: F159, F160
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Mr. Alix?, [1930s]; F159
      See also: F158, F160
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, Mr. Alix?, [1930s]; F160
      See also: F158, F159
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Wechanimaash (James) Owen & family, [1930s]; F161
      See also: A216, A220, A221, A222
      Owen, Wechaanimaash, (James)
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Noonaawas, A.I.H., [1930s] [1938?]; F162
      See also: A108
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, James Bearhair Owen [Mahkikaat or Maahkikaat?], [1930s]; F163
      See also: A212, A213, F154
    - Ojibwa, Pauingassi, Chief William Berens & A.I.H., [1930s]; F164
      See also: A8, A9, A10, A11, A12, A13, A17, A20, A286, F50, F51, F56, F88, F89, F92, F285
      Berens, William, Chief; Hallowell, A. Irving, (Alfred Irving), 1892-1974
    - Berens River rapids, 1938; F165
      See also: A74
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids or Duck Lake Campsite, [1930s]; F166
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, two girls looking at Rorschach blot., [1930s]; F167
    - Ojibwa, Grand Rapids, Edith Guimond, Alice Eaglestick, Eliza Eaglestick, and James Henry Boucher., [1930s]; F168
      Copy of photo in Ser. III, "Personality in Primitive Society as Approached Through Rorscahch Techniques"
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, John Keeper, Jonathan Keeper, Daniel Keeper, Lucy Keeper, and Harry Keeper, [1930s]; F169
      Harry Keeper
      Copy of photo in Ser. III, "Personality in Primitive Society as *
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Alexander Boucher, Ronald Keeper, Wilfred Boucher "wemtigozi" and Boniface Boucher., [1930s]; F170
      Copy of photo in Ser. III, "Personality in Primitive Society as Approached Through Rorschach Techniques"
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Lizzie Keeper, Mary Louise Keeper, and Augusta Keeper, 1930s; F171
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Henry Leveque, George Pascal, Thomas Boucher, Roderick Pascal and Xavier (Sabi) Owen, [1930s]; F172
    - Ojibwa, Little Grand Rapids, Jane Duck, Lillian Owen, James Owen, and Thomas Duck, [1930s]; F173
      Copy of photo in Ser. III, "Personality in Primitive Society as Approached Through Rorschach echniques.
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, George Howard Keeper, Charlie Bittern, David Alix, and Simon Alix., [1930s]; F174
      Copy of photo in Ser. III, "Personality in Primitive Society as Approached Through Roschach Techniques"
    - Ojibwa, Berens River, two women carrying cradleboards, [1930s]; F175
    - Ojibwa, Poplar Hill, Naamiwan's Dream dance lodge, 1933 [1930s]; F176
      See also: [A243, A244, A245?]
    - [Berens River?], [1930s] [1940?]; F177
      See also: F181
    - [Berens River?], [1930s] [1940?]; F178
      See also: F179, F180
    - [Berens River?], [1930s] [1940?]; F179
      See also: F178, F180
    - [Berens River?], [1930s] [1940?]; F180
      See also: F178, F179
    - [Berens River?], [1930s] [1940?]; F181
      See also: F177
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s] [1940?]; F182
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s] [1940?]; F183
      See also: F184
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s] [1940?]; F184
      See also: F183
    - Ojibwa, [Berens River], [1930s]; F185
    - [Berens River?], [1930s]; F186
      See also: F187
    - [Berens River?], [1930s]; F187
      See also: F186
    - [Ojibwa?], [Deer Lake?], [1930s]; F188
      Deer Lake Band
    - [Ojibwa?], Deer Lake, Ont., [1930s]; F189
    - [Ojibwa?], Deer Lake, Ont., [1930s]; F190
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake Sweet Grass & Hobbema [?], [1930s]; F191
      [From a trip to Saskatchewan, plains?] -- J. Brown
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Summer, 1931; F192
      See also: F193
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Summer, 1931; F193
      Camps
      See also: F192
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Summer, 1931; F194
      Donhoubuuss [sp?]
    - Cree, Fishing Lake, Ray Star, Summer, 1931; F195
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Saw a wolf, Summer, 1931; F196
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F197
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F198
      Threshing
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, Jimmy Fain, [1930s]; F199
      Ready for school in winter
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F200
      See also: F201
      Original photo from Saskatchewan *
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F201
      See also: F200
    - [Ojibwa?], Fishing Lake, [1930s]; F202